Preliminary Guide to the Women Work! records, 1979-2009 RL.01407
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Women Work! records
1975-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Women Work! The National Network for Women's Employment
RL.01407
17.1 Linear Feet
Women Work! improved women's economic security through job training, education, lobbying policymakers, and partnering with other national organizations. It was originally known as the Displaced Homemakers Network, and operated from 1978 until 2009. Accession (2009-0163) (12,375 items; 16.5 lin. ft.; dated 1979-2009) includes board materials, training guides and reports, program materials, conference files, newsletters and publications, news clippings and photocopies, photographs, slides, electronic files and images, and videos. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Women Work! Archives were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Historical Note
Women Work! began in the early 1970s as the Alliance for Displaced Homemakers, which sought to assist newly divorced, widowed, or abandoned women in re-entering the workforce after working as homemakers. It quickly grew thanks to the grassroots efforts of founders Tish Sommers, Laurie Shields, Milo Smith, and Barbara Dudley. In 1978, a national conference was held and the Displaced Homemakers Network was formed, providing a permanent presence for the group in Washington, DC. In 1993, the organization became Women Work! The National Network for Women's Employment, and expanded its scope to address the economic concerns that women face throughout their lives. Women Work! focused its efforts on job training for women; educating Congress and policy makers about women's economic and employment issues; and networking with other organizations to enhance women's economic security. Women Work! ceased operations in 2009.
Collection Overview
Accession (2009-0163) (16.5 lin. ft.; dated 1979-2009) includes board materials, training guides and reports, program materials, conference files, newsletters and publications, news clippings and photocopies, photographs, slides, electronic files and images, and videos. CDs and other electronic data files have been removed and transferred to Duke's ERM server. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Accession (2015-0112) (0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1975-1990) is an addition that includes board materials, training guides and reports, program materials, administrative records, correspondance, and copies of the Network News, the publication for the Displaced Homemakers Network.
Collection Arrangement
This collection has not been processed, and materials have not been arranged or described other than how they were presented by the donor. Certain fragile materials--especially electronic, audiovisual, and photographic materials--may require processing before use. Please contact Research Services with questions.
Photographs; Color slides; Videotapes; Occupational training for women; Unemployed women workers; Women -- Employment; Compact discs; Equal pay for equal work; Homemakers -- Employment; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Women Work! The National Network for Women's Employment
- Accession (2009-0163), 1979-2009, 11 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Accession (2009-0163) (12,375 items; 16.5 lin. ft.; dated 1979-2009) includes board materials, training guides and reports, program materials, conference files, newsletters and publications, news clippings and photocopies, photographs, slides, electronic files and images, and videos. Women Work! has been abbreviated to WW! when possible.
  - DVDs of Women Triumph and Women Work! movies (Box 1)
  - Audio cassettes, including tapes from conferences and luncheons, audio conferences, Displaced Homemakers Focus Group, board meetings, an oral history of Women Work!, and 3 miniature audio cassettes (Box 1)
  - 5 Betacam tapes, including Women Work! 20th Anniversary and the Transitions to Triumph video (Box 1)
  - 19 VHS tapes, including the 20th Anniversary Gala, political coverage, and news segments (Box 1)
  - Annual reports (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - We Work! magazine (volumes 1-3, 11 issues) (Box 2)
  - WW! conference programs, 1995-2008 (11 folders) (Box 2)
  - Publications, 1990s-2001 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Network News newsletters, 1980s-2005 (3) (Box 2)
  - Advocates Guides (Box 2)
  - Economic Equity Insider, 1990s-2004 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Transition Times, 1987-1992 (Box 2)
  - Transitions and Triumphs, 2001-2005 (Box 2)
  - Board files, 1980s (18 folders) (Box 2)
    Includes budgets, mailing lists, committee materials, memoranda, and meeting minutes.
  - Press, 1985, 1988-1989 (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Press (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Media Evaluations Status Reports, 1987 (10 folders, according to Region) (Box 3)
  - Press clippings from news conference, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Press (9) (Box 3)
  - Overcoming Obstacles, Winning Jobs (Box 3)
  - Displaced Homemakers Network subscription service (Box 3)
  - Reports and guides, 1980s-1990s (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Reports and guides, 1980s-1990s (Box 4)
  - Grants contracts/Women's Bureau Quarterly Reports, 1997-1998 (8 folders) (Box 4)
  - Insurance (6 folders) (Box 4)
  - Spokesperson Project (Box 4)
  - Displaced Homemakers Network Board, 1980s (11 folders) (Box 4)
    Includes funds, committees, mailings, and meeting files.
  - Tax seminar (Box 4)
  - State program training (Box 4)
  - Pittsburgh Junior League, 1982 (Box 4)
  - White House briefings, 1980s (Box 4)
  - Displaced Homemakers Network grant proposals, 1979-1982 (Box 4)
  - Grant proposals (Box 5)
  - Subscription service (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Bulk mailing (Box 5)
  - Finances and miscellaneous information, 1990s (Box 5)
  - Newsletter hot tips, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Network Know-How (Displaced Homemakers Network) (binder) (Box 5)
  - All in a Day's Work: Organizing for Women's Economic Power, Nov. 8-10, 1987 (binder) (Box 5)
  - Jobs That Pay! Non-traditional Occupations, April 2000 (binder) (Box 5)
  - Guide to Non-traditional Occupations for Mid-Life and Older Women, March 1993 (binder) (Box 5)
  - Getting IT Across! Recruiting women to IT careers, 2002 (binder) (Box 5)
  - On the Right Track: empowerment and workplace rights, Sept. 1996 (binder) (Box 5)
  - Superstores, Schools, and Sewers: Understanding local economy, Dec. 1996 (binder) (Box 5)
  - Newsletters and printed guides, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Program directories, 1998-2000 (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Printed guides and reports, 1980s-1990s (4 folders) (Box 5)
  - Publications: newsletters, guides, announcements, 1980s-2000s (Box 6)
  - Financial report, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Assessment reports, 2002-2007 (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - E-News, 2007 (binder) (Box 6)
  - Economic Equity Insider newsletters, 2005-2006 (Box 6)
  - News clippings, 1975-2007 (14 folders) (Box 6)
    These clippings are in clear plastic sleeves and are organized by year. In many cases, a donor-created index of the articles is available at the front of each folder.
  - IDA Case (Box 7)
  - RITA (Box 7)
  - Value of Homemaking (Box 7)
  - Women Vote (Box 7)
  - Op Ed materials (Box 7)
  - Media coverage (Box 7)
  - Work Your Image (Box 7)
  - CTFA (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Logos/letterhead (Box 7)
  - Press conferences, 1990s (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Long range planning (Box 7)
  - Developing a state network training (Box 7)
  - LEAD Manuals, 1995-1996 (6 bound manuals) (Box 7)
    Manuals are for individual states: Missouri, Michigan, Oregon, and Alabama.
  - NCWO-Survey (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Bank of America (Box 7)
  - Barbara Lee Foundation: GOTV (Box 7)
  - CREW (Box 7)
  - Fashion Takes Action (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Impact statement (Box 7)
  - Constituent letters (Box 7)
  - Appropriations, 1993-1995 (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - Senate (Box 7)
  - House (Box 7)
  - WIA (Box 7)
  - Vocational Education (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - U.S. Dept. of Labor: Women's Bureau, 1990s-2001 (6 folders) (Box 7)
  - State conferences, 2004-2005 ( 10 folders) (Box 8)
  - History of Displaced Homemakers Network (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Strategic Philanthropy Investments report (Box 8)
  - Speeches (Box 8)
  - NEFE (Box 8)
  - Work Your Image! (Box 8)
  - CWJT (Box 8)
  - Recruiting Women for NTO (Box 8)
  - Approp. RITA, 2007 (Box 8)
  - Newspaper printouts and clippings, 2008-2009 (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Magazines, 2000s (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Displaced Homemakers Network pilot project legislation, 1970s-1980s (Box 8)
  - Personnel and participant policies, 2002-2005 (Box 8)
  - Publications, mail, handouts, 1990s-2000s (Box 8)
  - Frito Lay/WW! partnership, 2007 (Box 8)
  - Reports and miscellaneous materials, 1990-2008 (Box 8)
  - Strategic planning, 2008 (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Balanced scorecard (Box 8)
  - Recruiting for the IT Age, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Network News, 1979-2005 (5 folders) (Box 9)
  - Publications, 1990s-2000s (Box 9)
  - GITA final report (Box 9)
  - CREW retention final report (Box 9)
  - WANTO 2002 (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Dislocated Worker Earmark, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Organization restructuring: Board Report Card (Box 9)
  - Women's Bureau, 2000-2009 (6 folders) (Box 9)
  - WW! Resources, tip sheets (Box 9)
  - Manuscript and copyright agreements, 2004-2006 (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Public Policy Summit, 1998 (binder) (Box 9)
  - Photo album pages (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1 photo album (Box 10)
  - Historical photographs (Box 10)
  - Network News and Success Story photographs, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Photographs and negatives (Box 10)
  - Congressional pact briefing negatives (2 envelopes) (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous color photographs (17 envelopes) (Box 10)
    Photographs from events, conferences, speaking engagements, and other programs. There are 6 large envelopes of miscellaneous or ungrouped photographs, and there are 11 smaller envelopes where photographs were labelled or bound together.
  - 6 photo albums (Box 11)
  - Slides (3 boxes) (Box 11)
  - Color photographs (Box 11)
  - Photographs, rolls 1-13 (Box 11)
  - 3 WW! tote bags (Box 11)
  - Poster: Behind Many Successful Men and Women in America is a Displaced Homemaker, 1980s (Oversize-folder 1)
- Accession (2015-0112), 1975-1990
  - Displaced Homemaker Network Legislation, October 1975-July 1977 (Box 12)
  - Displaced Homemaker Legislation, September 1977-October 1980 (Box 12)
  - Displaced Homemaker Network Foundations, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Displaced Homemakers, National Training Conference, October 1978 (Box 12)
  - Displaced Homemakers Network Program Directories, 1979-1981 (Box 12)
  - Displaced Homemaker Network Administrative Records, January 1980-August 1984 (Box 12)
  - National Displaced Homemakers Network Report, 1990 (Box 12)
  - National News (Newsletter), January 1979-December 1983 (Box 12)